I- I'm going home!
You're leaving? What's wrong?
Miyao!
Weren't you going to tell me how high schoolers make progress?
I guess that Miyao kid couldn't stand the tension in the room.
Either that, or he knows something...
I wonder why...
Whenever I look at this girl, my heart starts to tighten up.
So that means this girl really does have feelings for Haruo-kun.
How could this be, aren't these girls still in their first year of high school?
Yet a 19 year old like me... Forget a love triangle, I haven't even been in a relationship yet!
What's the difference between me and my spacey little sister Akira?
Unclean... It's unclean!
If I stay in this slimy atmosphere any longer...
My innocent heart will wear away!
Huh, you too? Where are you going?
I'm feeling kind of dizzy so I'm going downstairs to chat with your mom.
Are you okay?
You little playboy!
What was that for?
kazoekirenai hodo
数え切れないほど
Countless times
kurikaeshi ta tatakai no hibi no naka omoidasu
繰り返し闘いの日々の中　思い出す
I remember those days of continuous battling
tanoshii koto dake jibun dake no basho
楽しいことだけ 自分だけの場所
At a place with only happiness and myself
ashisuto wa iranai
アシストはいらない
I don't need assistance
sore de yokatta no ni
それでよかったのに
This is good enough
mihakken no bagu ga kakikaete yura bi iku
未発見のバグが書き換えて揺らび行く
Rewrite and sway the undiscovered bugs
hashiridasu kono kodou ga
走り出す　この鼓​動が
My heartbeat starts running
machigai to shite mo kamawanai
間違いとしても　構わない
Even if it's wrong, I don't care
doushite tsutaetai kimochi dake ga
どうして　伝えたい気持ちだけが
Why do the feelings I want to convey
kono te o surinukeru no
この手をすり抜けるの
Slip through my hands?
yureru hibana no you na kono jikan dake wa
揺れる　火花の様な　この時間だけは
Shaking like a spark just for this moment
hanasanai dakishimeru yo
離さない　抱きしめるよ
I'll embrace it and never let it go
motto takaku tooi basho e tsurete iku kara
もっと高く遠い場所へ　連れていくから
It'll take me to a higher and farther place
Oh, what's wrong Makoto-chan?
Things are getting really slimy and messed up upstairs.
Oh?
Things are getting slimy and messed up upstairs, you say?
I'm just a kid so I don't understand anything.
Aww~ there, there. It's okay, don't be upset.
Why don't you and I just go back to our game of vulgar shiritori?
Yeah, let's play!
W-What's with this atmosphere?
This is almost like when two people go head-to-head, pitting their honor against one another on the battlefield...
The atmosphere of an arena overflowing with blood lust!
Um...
What I was trying to say earlier was...
For some time now, I've been wanting to have a match with you on a fighting game, Oono-san.
A match?
Yaguchi-kun, did you get VF2 for the Saturn?
Y-Yeah, of course.
It's fine if you want to have a match
but I only have one arcade controller.
All of a sudden, a battle between Oono and Hidaka has begun...
But... This is bound to be interesting.
I never thought that today I'd finally be able to have my battle with Oono-san.
Will she treat this as just a game? Or will she...
TN: Reverse Body Check
Youshi Senrin!
TN: Double Palm
Launching into a chain combo while she's still recovering, and going into a Byakko Soushouda!
She's fully serious.
My health is already down to only a quarter.
TN: (a low punch reversal)
Honshin Tanda!
Can't even land a single hit...
She lost without saying a single word... This is pretty serious.
Tanyokuchou!
A high kick reversal...
Gaimon Chouchuu!
A mid punch reversal...
No matter how much I strike at her, she counters my every move!
You can practically see Oono-san's stubborness in her defence...
And it's like she can see right through me...
Souhakushu!
A low kick reversal...
I don't want to lose!
This no longer has anything to do with Yaguchi-kun.
I just want to win as a gamer!
Hidaka's pushing back!
It's a battle of honor: girl vs girl.
Well aren't you a carefree guy?
As I thought this is serious...
She didn't say anything after losing either.
She never says anything though!
When did the two of them get so strong?
Where have they been practicing?
She's not letting the gamepad slow her down...
As I thought, Oono-san is incredible.
But... I've been training myself up as well.
I won't back down!
TN: Stun Palm of Doom
Hougeki Unshin Soukoshou!!!
You're ten years to early!
A three part attack that goes from a Banken to a Youshi Senrin to a Soushou.
Otherwise known as the Akira Special!
It's my loss...
Oono-san, will you fight me again sometime?
Someday, I want to show you that I can win.
W-What? Y-You want to show her you can win at what?
At video games...
Why would you-
What's your problem?
Akira, don't leave your big sister behind!
She's as mysterious as always.
True.
Women are a mystery.
And it's a man's duty to try and unravel that mystery.
I'm in Soul Smasher hell...
He just keeps shamelessy shooting them off!
TN: Soul Choke
You can use Oni Kubi Hineri if you want.
If you can get close enough, that is.
We're always gonna pick Pyron when you join the game.
Until you become sick and tired of fighting against him.
Why are you all ganging up on me?
You've committed a sin... The sin of stepping on the light of our Hidaka-shi's heart.
Accept the virtual punishment for your sins.
You're that so-called Mizonokuchi Force led by Nikotama Felicia, aren't you?
But shouldn't I be part of the force too, since Mizunokuchi is my home base?
We won't accept it...
A gamer who's loved by women isn't a real gamer!
What the heck?
Hey, hold on there you guys!
What are you doing ganging up on someone like that?
As fellow gamers, you should be getting along.
Honestly...
It seems like you've get some strange people idolizing you, Hidaka.
This used to be such a healing place...
But now eveyone's so savage.
Yeah.
Oono-san hasn't been coming here lately either.
What?
Why would you bring up Oono?
No reason.
Well, whatever.
Hidaka, let's play a round of Virtua 2.
We can find out who's stronger, your Sarah or my Kage.
Not today. I want to play Samurai Showdown III.
Hey, dickface.
If you keep bothering Hidaka-shi, I'll give you a taste of my punch that registers 60K on the punching game.
60 kilos?
And I might have to bust out my 32K grip strength, got it?
Isn't that less than average?
And my back muscles measure in at 90K, isn't that scary?
These guys are pretty funny.
Hidaka-shi's saying you're an eyesore.
Why can't you get that through your head?
Isn't that right, Hidaka-shi?
It might be the case.
I see. Then I'll withdraw for now.
But prepare yourselves, Mizunokuchi Force.
Hey Koharu-chan, don't be like that.
Saying such mean stuff... It's not like you, Koharu-chan.
Lately, whenever I'm around Yaguchi-kun, my personality changes for the worse.
I gradually start to want to punch him in the face, or give him a good kick.
I wonder if all the fighting games she plays are turning her into a big sadist.
I wonder what it is...
This strange, uneasy feeling...
Damn it, this is starting to get annoying.
Damn, what's with that Mizunokuchi Force? This smells like a conspiracy.
The world of fighting games is a world of competition.
A savage arena for people to settle their differences.
That's why you shouldn't get too close to others...
You should be a lone wolf.
Just like Oono.
I'm lonely...
Shibuya
What a dangerous town...
In my quest to find a place that I could belong, I came to the wild city of Shibuya...
TN: The city from Final Fight
As usual, the dangerous air around here reminds me of Metro City.
Don't fuck with me!
I'll kill you!
But it's the perfect place for a runaway like me.
It's been a while... since I last left Mizunokuchi.
Well... If you're looking for an arcade in Shibuya...
Shibuya Kaikan Monaco!
Including the basement, it's got 5 stories packed with all sorts of games.
Even if you stayed here all day long, you'd never get tired of it.
It's a battlefield where the powerful gather...
I guess I'll spend all my time fighting here, using overthrowing the Mizunokuchi Force as my motivation.
Go! Get him!
Destroy the general!
Kaiser Knuckle by Taito.
He's strong! Way too strong!
That boss is seriously strong!
He's horribly strong! Actually, he's just horrible!
The ultimate boss that appears at the end if you manage to fulfill certain conditions... The General!
A character whose impregnable defense sends many gamers spiraling into depression.
Even Gamest Magazine could only write "do your best" as a strategy for defeating him... Truly a fearsome existence.
What's with this 3 direction projectile?
This has got to be cheating!
His atrocious 3 hit sliding kick!
His spectacular high kick that even counters arials!
And even if you're this far apart...
He'll still suck you in with his disgustingly long grab reach!
And then there's his unbeatable teleport!
What's wrong with this boss?
The developer who made him must've been a real sadist!
What are you looking at?
You making a fool out of us for trying to overthrow the general?
No, I wasn't...
Don't make us tickle you, you bastard!
Why don't you try it then, if you think you're so great?
You know what'll happen if you can't beat him, right?
No, I don't know...
What's going on today?
I keep getting bullied by these arcade groups...
I never thought I'd suddenly be dragged into a fight with the General...
If I lose this, they might just end up tickling me to death.
So he'll use Wulong, huh?
So, how far do you think he'll get?
If it's the General...
Actually when I was in middle school, I watched Oono challenge him.
At that time her strategy was...
Oono! If you end up defeating this terrible general, you'll go down in Mizunokuchi history!
She lost that time, but...
Oono, right now I'll be making use of the strategy you came up with!
TN: Dragon Energy Slash
Ryuukizan, then a low kick!
What's with that?
That's all there is to it!
It's a brilliant strategy to confuse the general, who moves based on his opponents attacks!
Even Oono looked helpless when she broke the attack sequence.
He's winning against the general!
So instead of letting him trap you, you have to trap him instead!
So that means no matter what you try, it really is impossible to win with a full front attack!
But that's fine!
We just want to see the General defeated!
Ryuukizan, then a low kick!
Concentrate...
Move without thinking, like a robot.
I'll surpass this wall that not even Oono could overcome!
Right here, right now, I'm inheriting Oono's will!
Kill him!
That was awesome!
This isn't a dream, right?
I'm actually going to see what happens after the General is defeated?
So when you beat the general, his base gets destroyed!
So the general and his base were one and the same!
I did it.
I managed to replicate Oono's strategy after watching her do it...
Hey, you did a great job!
You're no ordinary guy, are you?
A rising star of fighting games has appeared!
I'd really like to share some of this joy with Oono,but...
Hey, newbie! How would you like to join our Shibuya Squad?
Shibuya Squad?
The truth is, lately these outsiders have been talking about coming in and taking over Shibuya.
We don't like the sound of that, so we're gathering comrades for a counter attack.
Who are these outsiders?
The Mizunokuchi Force.
The Mizunokuchi Force!
Those guys... They were doing something so outrageous without even consulting me, Beastly Finger Yaguchi?
Then that means Hidaka's part of this too... I don't like it.
What do you say?
Will you strike down the Mizunokuchi Force with us?
A battle against the Shibuya Squad?
No one told me anything about this...
Despite their looks, they're actually quite hot-headed...
And it sound like they're frustrated at being treated like outsiders in Shibuya.
Why do something so dangerous?
I don't want to fight anyone.
Lately, different regional teams have been challenging each other less often...
But this sort of cultural exchange is a wonderful thing.
Sure, but this time it just sounds like a normal fight.
I wonder what it is...
I still don't want to get into some sort of turf war with fellow game lovers, but..
Lately, it feels like things have been falling apart...
SF Alpha 2 has a unique flavor to it!
I'm going to try Rolento.
Gen for me!
I'm gonna keep using Rose.
But really, it's gonna be Sakura, right?
Yaguchi-kun is never around these days...
Even thought SF Alpha 2 finally came out...
I want to apologise for what happened before, but...
I can't bring myself to visit Yaguchi-kun's house.
Why do I keep messing up like this?
Haruo...
You really have been corrupted by Shibuya...
Sitting around on the ground like that...
I'm not corrupted!
I just heard that Shibuya's a town where it's okay to sit on the ground.
And what's with those clothes?
This isn't like you.
Well... I got these from the Shibuya Squad guys.
You look so much better in those lame clothes you usually wear though.
You said "Haah?" like a delinquent!
I knew it! You really have fallen to the lever of the Shibuya folk!
I didn't fall! I didn't fall to any level!
Man... Darius Gaiden music is so rad.
Enough to get even someone like me who's bad at shooting games hooked on it.
I still can't beat it with no continues, but my route is...
A -> C -> F -> I -> N -> S -> X
Thank goodness...
This part of him is still the same old Haruo.
Playing around at a downtown arcade like this...
For an honor student like me, it's like I've gone down the wrong path...
Quit fucking around!
Are these double up slots like, impossible to win?
Unbelievable!
Girls these days are crazy...
What's with those socks?
It looks like some sort of animal leg.
It's totally rigged, isn't it?
Hey Haruo, I know you're upset about being bullied by the Mizunokuchi Force...
But you can't just spend all your time in Shibuya.
You know, we came here today because we were worried about you.
Yeah but...
Shibuya's actually not that bad a place.
There's plenty of nice people here.
The guy playing Sando-R over there is Shibuya Drill-san.
That's Taro-san, who loves Puzzle Bubble 2.
And then there's Jay-san from overseas. They're all really nice.
Are you sure about that?
No one who likes Sando-R or Puzzle Bubble 2 could be a bad person!
Haruo!
You know you can't meet up with Oono-san at Mizunokuchi if you stay here, right?
I-It's not like I go to arcades just to see her.
Besides...
She hasn't been coming around lately... to the arcade.
H-Help me...
What happened, Doi?
They're mugging people and stealing their Air Maxes...
Air Max muggings?
Also their jeans...
Jeans muggings?
They also Mug mugged me for the mug I was drinking out of...
Who did that?
Now that I look at them that guy's jeans look horrible, don't they?
Hey you, you need to stop this heinous evil act!
You're the reason arcades have such a poor image!
That's right! It's all your fault!
Huh? I literally can't believe what I'm hearing.
Like what are you even getting so mad about?
You bunch of BK's!
What's a BK?
It means someone who's creepy.
What the heck?
I should be the one calling you that as a high schooler!
Prepare to get BTFO.
BTFO?
It means she's going to kill you.
What language is she speaking?
Fucking randos!
If you keep fucking around I'll kick your asses in 5 seconds flat!
You there... Stop your fighting.
Who the fuck?
TN: Lau is a character from VF2
Lau...
Numata-sensei!
Those kids are my former students. I ask you to release them.
Seriously, you're a teacher?
That's fucking hilarious!
I'm going to beat you up, take your money and go to 'buya for some 'oke!
TN: Crescent kick
Senpuuga!
He's being juggled!
She's finishing him off with a mid-air combo!
He's down! Will he get back up?
It's no use, ring out!
What are you shouting about, Haruo?
As usual, you guys are playing around in a place like this.
Touno-sensei!
By the way, what's up with your clothes?
I was so proud of you during those high school exams...
But I guess you never really change, Yaguchi-kun?
Uh, right...
I don't care if you're a teacher from another school or what. You can't stop our rampage!
Sensei, it's dangerous!
S-So strong!
Whatever she did, I couldn't even see it!
You'll regret this!
Curse you women! I'll get you in round two!
Please wait there.
As students, what do you think your main responsibilities are?
...Studying.
...Studies.
80% studying and 20% playing
I think you mean 10% playing, don't you Yaguchi-kun!
There's a misunderstanding!
They only got involved because they were trying to save me!
In fact, you should be praising them for fighting instead of just leaving me behind!
You kids... You were thinking that much about your friend...
Friend?
You guys...
Haruo...
Just as I thought, Shibuya really is a dangerous place.
We'll be heading back to Mizunokuchi first.
Hey Haruo!
We ran into some guys from Mizunokuchi.
We were trying to figure out the game we should be competing with.
The new SF Alpha 2 or Samurai Showdown III.
Some people suggested Fighting Vipers too.
We also talked about maybe making it a cotton candy making contest.
What the heck?
What kind of game is this? You're fighting a fish?
Are there any mola mola in this?
Actually, there is...
I wanna see!
Yaguchi-kun is the first player of the Shibuya Squad?
I won't wish upon the stars
hoshi ni negai wo kaketari shinai
星に願いをかけたりしない
I won't wonder "what if my wish will come true"
“moshimo negai ga kanau nara” nante omowanai
「もしも願いが叶うなら」なんて思わない
The teacher won't teach us
sensei mo oshiete kurenai
先生も教えてくれない
You can tell by the score
tensuu ja oshihakarenai
点数じゃ推し量れない
I don't need eyes of envy
senbou no manazashi wa iranai
羨望の眼差しは要らない
It was my first love
hajimete no rabu datta
初めてのラブだった
I don't know any love spells
koi no wo majinai shiranai
恋のおまじない知らない
I have never done "girl talk"
gaaruzu tooku shita koto nai
ガールズトークしたことない
The tutorial does not start
chuutoriaru hajimaranai
チュートリアル始まらない
It was my first map
hajimete no chizu datta
初めての地図だった
Now I reach for the sky
ima sora ni te wo nobasu
今空に手を伸ばす
You can ear the popping sound of sparks
hibana no moeteku oto ga hajikeru
火花の燃えてく音が弾ける
Heart throbbing in a world I have never seen before
mita koto no nai sekai ni mune ga naru
見たことのない世界に胸が鳴る
The field gets bigger as the wind blows
kaze to tomo ni fiirudo ga hirogatteku
風と共にフィールドが広がってく
The dots are connecting
ten to ten ga tsunagatteku
点と点が繋がってく
(an unknown world map)
announ waarudo mappu
アンノウン・ワールドマップ
It starts a chain reaction
rensa hannou hirogatteku
連鎖反応広がってく
(an unknown world map)
announ waarudo mappu
アンノウン・ワールドマップ